nccn.org 2006-12-12

# NCCN Privacy Policy

## NCCN Privacy Statement

The National Comprehensive Cancer Network, Inc., (NCCN) is issuing this privacy statement to keep you, our valued user, informed of activities in place to ensure your privacy. This privacy statement covers the site www.nccn.org. If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact Alex Yakovlev, Vice President, Information Systems, by E-mail or telephone (215.690.0258). 

## Information Collection and Use

#### Information Collection

NCCN is the sole owner of the information collected on www.nccn.org. NCCN collects information from our users at several different points on this web site. 

**NCCN Clinical Practice Guidelines in Oncology™ Registration**

NCCN requests information on a voluntary basis from users of its Clinical Practice Guidelines in Oncology™. NCCN uses this information to contact the user about services on our site for which he/she has expressed interest and to advise users about future updates to this site. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as specialty or year of graduation), but encouraged so NCCN can provide a more personalized experience on its site. 

**NCCN Conference and Symposia Registration**

NCCN requests information from the user on our annual conference registration form. Here a user must provide contact information (such as name and mailing address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes for conference registration fees and/or hotel deposits. If NCCN cannot process an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user. NCCN also requests contact information from users registering for regional guidelines symposia. This information is used to confirm registration data. Users do not need to provide financial information to register for regional guidelines symposia.

**NCCN Drugs & Biologics Compendium™ Registration**

NCCN does require users of the NCCN Drugs & Biologics Compendium™ to register to access this data on the NCCN site. Required information includes first and last name, username, password and e-mail address. NCCN uses this information to contact the user about services on this site for which he/she has expressed interest and to advise users about future updates to this site. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as specialty or year of graduation), but encouraged so NCCN can provide a more personalized experience on its site. 

**NCCN On-Demand Learning Registration**

NCCN does require visitors to register to use NCCN On-Demand Learning archived presentations. Required information includes first and last name, degree, title, organization, mailing address, username, password and e-mail address. NCCN uses this information to process CE credit, to contact the user about services on this site for which he has expressed interest, and to advise users about future updates to this site. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as specialty or year of graduation), but encouraged so NCCN can provide a more personalized experience on its site. 

**Orders for NCCN Resources**

NCCN does require information from users who order NCCN presentations on CD-ROM, NCCN Guidelines resources such as CD-ROMs or Pocket Guides, Treatment Guidelines for Patients, and other NCCN resources. Required information includes first and last name, shipping address, and e-mail address. This information is used to fill requesters’ orders. If NCCN cannot process an order, the information is used to contact the user. 

**NCCN Online Surveys**

From time-to-time, NCCN may provide you the opportunity participate in surveys on our web site. NCCN does not require information from users to complete these periodic online surveys about NCCN programs, services, and resources. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as specialty or year of graduation), but encouraged so NCCN can enhance its programs, services and resources. 

NCCN uses a third party service provider to conduct these surveys; that company will be prohibited from using our users’ personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We will not share personally identifiable information you provide through a survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice.

**“Refer A Colleague”**

If you choose to use NCCN’s referral service to tell colleagues about this site or NCCN programs, services, or resources, NCCN will ask for your colleagues’ names and e-mail addresses. NCCN will automatically send a one-time e-mail inviting your colleague(s) to visit the site. Those whom you refer may contact NCCN to request that we remove this information from our database. 

**Cookies**

"Cookies" are small pieces of information stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Cookies are only read by the server that placed them, and are unable to do such things as run programs on your computer, plant viruses, or harvest your personal information. The use of cookies is very common on the Internet.

NO personal information about you is gathered or stored in the cookies placed by the NCCN web site. NO personal information about you is gathered through the use of these cookies. NCCN uses cookies mainly to understand web site usage and traffic statistics. NCCN uses NetTracker to analyze traffic to this web site so we can understand our visitors’ needs and continually improve this site for them. NetTracker collects only anonymous, aggregate statistics. 

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. By changing the options on your web browser or using certain software programs, you can control how and whether cookies will be accepted by your browser. Please note that it is possible to block cookie activity from certain web sites while permitting cookies from sites you trust. 

#### Information Use

**Profile**

NCCN stores information that it collects through log files and/or third parties to create a profile of our users. A profile is stored information that NCCN maintains on individual users which details their viewing preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to users’ personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for users. These profiles may be used to tailor users’ visits to our web site and to direct pertinent marketing promotions to them. NCCN does not share your profile with other third parties. 

**Log Files**

Like most web site servers, NCCN’s uses log files. These include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and user activity within this web site to analyze trends, administer the site, track users’ movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. NCCN uses a tracking utility called NetTracker that uses log files to analyze user movement. 

**Communications from the Site**

_Special Offers and Updates_

Established users of the NCCN Drugs & Biologics Compendium™ and NCCN On-Demand Learning; NCCN conference and regional guidelines symposia registrants; and users who opt-in while ordering NCCN resources will occasionally receive information on new or updated NCCN programs, services, or resources. Opting in means users have asked to be contacted about NCCN programs, services, and resources. Users may opt-in via business reply mail or e-mail, on conference and symposia registration forms, or while registering to access NCCN services online. 

You may unsubscribe at any time by contacting us.

**Sharing**

_Legal Disclaimer_

Though NCCN makes every effort to preserve user privacy, NCCN may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein NCCN has a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order, or legal process served on our web site. 

_Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)_

NCCN shares aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. For example, NCCN may describe the number of users by geography or medical specialty. This is not linked to any personally identifiable information. 

_Third Party Intermediaries_

NCCN uses an outside fulfillment company to process and ship orders for NCCN products; an e-mail broadcast company to send e-mail announcements about NCCN events and resources; a web hosting company to provide online access to NCCN presentations; an online survey vendor to periodically survey groups of NCCN users; and a credit card processing company to bill users for conference registration. These companies do not retain, share, store, or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. Registration for NCCN’s annual conference and regional guidelines symposia consists of a link to a site hosted by Peopleware; to view their Internet Registration Module Security statement, go to <http://www.pware.com/admin/securityStatement.htm>. Registration for NCCN On-Demand Learning consists of a link to a site hosted by e-city interactive; to view this privacy statement, go to [http://nccn.cmeport.com](http://nccn.cmeport.com/). Registration to order NCCN resources online consists of a link to a site hosted by NiceLines Direct Mail; to view this privacy statement, go to <http://pdf.nicelines.com/nccn/web%20privacy%20policy.pdf>. Registration to access NCCN surveys is hosted on a site by Survey Monkey; to view this privacy statement, go to <http://www.surveymonkey.com/>

**Links**

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that the National Comprehensive Cancer Network, Inc. is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. NCCN encourages users to be aware when they leave the NCCN site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this web site. 

#### Security

This web site takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the web site, their information is protected both online and off-line. 

When NCCN’s registration forms ask users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the industry-standard encryption software - Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). While on a secure page, such as a registration form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just “surfing.” 

While NCCN uses SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, NCCN also does everything in its power to protect user information off-line. All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in NCCN offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, a billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure, locked environment. 

If users have any questions about the security at www.nccn.org, they can send an e-mail. 

#### Supplementation of Information 

For this web site to properly fulfill its obligation to users, it is necessary for NCCN to supplement the information we receive with information from 3rd party sources. 

**Address Verification**

NCCN uses PCCharge Pro for credit card processing services to verify a user’s address for credit card processing. 

#### Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information

If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, e-mail or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, NCCN provides a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users’ personally identifiable information. This can usually be done by E-mailing our User Support. 

#### Notification of Changes

If NCCN decides to change its privacy policy, NCCN will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places deemed appropriate so our users are always aware of what information NCCN collects, how it is used, and under what circumstances, if any, NCCN discloses it. NCCN will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

If, however, NCCN is going to use users’ personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, NCCN will notify users via e-mail. Users will have a choice as to whether or not NCCN uses their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if NCCN makes any material changes in its privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, NCCN will post a prominent notice on its web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where NCCN posts a notice we will also e-mail users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices. 

#### Contact Information

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us.
